<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priyam Das</title>
    <link>https://priyamdas.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://priyamdas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Priyam Das</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://priyamdas.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Priyam Das</title>
      <link>https://priyamdas.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://priyamdas.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:39:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priyamdas.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-projects&#34;&gt;Current Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;human-autonomy-and-engagement&#34;&gt;Human Autonomy and Engagement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-participants-are-given-the-option-to-choose-the-types-of-images-to-classify&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://priyamdas.github.io/research/choice_hu7cacd743dac003bcf57fd1d96e3be5e3_161966_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Participants are given the option to choose the types of images to classify.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://priyamdas.github.io/research/choice_hu7cacd743dac003bcf57fd1d96e3be5e3_161966_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1483&#34; height=&#34;868&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Participants are given the option to choose the types of images to classify.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

When scientists usually run human behavioral experiments, especially online, the researcher has total control over the experiment flow and the participant simply reacts to the stimuli presented. This works well enough, but we wondered whether giving participants more agency during the experiment would have an effect on their engagement and performance on the task. To investigate this we devised a series of classification tasks where participants are asked to label images of various grocery items. Depending on the task, participants are allowed to choose the category of images that they label, the number of images in each category to label, or even when to quit the experiment. The performance on the classification task, in terms of accuracy and number of images classified, of participants who are given agency is compared to that of participants who aren&amp;rsquo;t given any agency and go through a &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-effect-of-practice-in-overcoming-age-related-performance-gaps&#34;&gt;The Effect of Practice in Overcoming Age-Related Performance Gaps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been fairly well studied that younger adults learn faster and perform better on cognitive tasks testing memory and multitasking ability compared to adults even just 10 years older. This performance gap only increases as the age gap gets larger. However, could the older person ever match or even surpass the younger person&amp;rsquo;s performance given unlimited time to practice the task?
We are investigating this question using data obtained from popular brain training website 
&lt;a href=&#34;www.lumosity.com&#34;&gt;Lumosity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
